Guide to the Records of the Research Institute for the Study of Man's (RISM) Study of Chronic Marihuana Users in Jamaica (The Ganja Study) RISM.RG.12
New York University Archives
Records of the Research Institute for the Study of Man's (RISM) Study of Chronic Marihuana Users in Jamaica (The Ganja Study)
1970-1981
1970
New York University Archives
Research Institute for the Study of Man
RISM.RG.12
30.5 Linear Feet in 43 boxes
The Study of Chronic Marihuana Users in Jamaica (The Ganja Project) is a collection of materials relating to an anthropological and medical study of the long-term effects of cannabis smoking. It was commissioned by the National Institute of Mental Health in 1970 and conducted by the Research Institute for the Study of Man, in collaboration with the University of the West Indies, between 1970 and 1972. Materials include human subject data, background research on the physiological and psychological effects of cannabis use, the legal issues surrounding research involving controlled substances, and published materials relating to the study.
Provenance
The collection was donated to the New York University Archives by the Research Institute for the Study of Man in 2006. In 2017 an accretion of materials was transferred to the University Archives from the Reed Foundation; the accession number associated with this gift is 2017.023.
Access Restrictions
Restrictions apply to certain materials in Series I: Human Subject Data and will therefore not be displayed in this inventory. For further information regarding restrictions, please contact the New York University Archives.
Some restricted materials pertaining mainly to finances, internal administration, and private information remain at the Reed Foundation and are closed to researchers.
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the collection consists of human subject data from medical analyses conducted in 1970. There exists a substantial amount of background research material for the study relating to existing research on the effects of cannabis smoking and other drug use. Other background research includes an assessment of the legal status of marihuana use in Jamaica, which was produced for the study, and materials examining the legal issues related to clinical studies involving illegal substances. This research includes pamphlets from groups such as NORML and nearly two years of issues of The U.S. Journal of Drug and Alcohol Dependence. Also included are press clippings, book reviews, magazines, and journals with content relating to the published results of the Study of Chronic Marihuana Users in Jamaica, as well as the final report as issued to the National Institute of Mental Health. Data from the ethnographic study of Jamaican communities are not part of The Ganja Project collection.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading then chronologically within each subject/author heading.
The files are grouped into five series.
Missing Title
Human Subject Data
Subject Files
Reports
Journals, Articles, and Reprints
Newspapers and Clippings
Biographical / Historical
The Study of Chronic Marihuana Users in Jamaica was initiated at the invitation of the Center for Studies of Narcotic and Drug Abuse of the National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) and carried out by the Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) in collaboration with the Faculty of Medicine at the University of the West Indies (UWI). The research program was designed to provide data on the clinical and social effects of chronic cannabis smoking in Jamaica, the first study to be undertaken in a natural as well as laboratory setting. Preparation for the study involved negotiation with several agencies within the Government of Jamaica, which at the time prohibited the cultivation, use and possession of cannabis. Discussions with authorities in the Jamaican government and the University of the West Indies resulted in full support for the project. Agreements were made for the protection and privacy of field workers, informants, subjects and staff, and arrangements were made for facilities to conduct clinical studies of long-term effects of smoking cannabis. Combining anthropological and medical research methodology, the study began in June 1970 with anthropological field studies which were conducted over the first 18 months. Sixty volunteer subjects were selected from these communities and admitted to the University Hospital in November 1970. Thirty marijuana users with a history of at least ten years of past use, and 30 non-smokers, underwent medical and psychological examinations over a period of six days. Anthropological and clinical data analysis was completed in February 1972, and findings were reported to the NIMH and the Jamaican Government in March of the same year. Controversy surrounded publication of the results of the study. They did not confirm existing research concerning negative consequences derived from the use of cannabis, most particularly the "anti-motivational" aspect often associated with the use of the substance. In 1973, a Conference on Cross Cultural Perspectives on Cannabis was held in Chicago preceding the IXth International Congress of the International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences. Supported by the NIMH, the conference was attended by over sixty scientists involved in various aspects of research on the complexities of cannabis in relation to man and culture, representing the fields of anthropology, botany, genetics, pharmacology, psychiatry and sociology. The proceedings, edited by Vera Rubin, were published as Cannabis and Culture in 1975.
References Rubin, Vera, and Lambros Comitas. Ganja in Jamaica: A Medical Anthropological Study of Chronic Marihuana Use. The Hague and Paris: Mouton and Co., 1975. Rubin, Vera, ed. Cannabis and Culture. Paris and The Hague: Mouton. 1975.
Cannabis.; Drug abuse.; Drugs -- Physiological effect.; Marijuana.; Marijuana -- Jamaica.; Research Institute for the Study of Man; National Institute of Mental Health (U.S.). Center for Studies of Narcotic and Drug Abuse; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica). Department of Social and Preventive Medicine; Rubin, Vera D.; Comitas, Lambros
- Series II: Subject Files
  - Bibliographies, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Conferences, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Chevannes, Barry Correspondence, Reports, and Questionnaire, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Comitas, Lambros, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Chromosome Study (Thorburn), 1972 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Reports - Thorbourne, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Vitae (UWI), undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Cruickshank Preliminary Medical Report, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Dreher, Melanie, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Altered States of Conscience Conference, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Employees, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Educational References, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Field Assistants, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Final Report, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Comments on Report - General, 1972, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Grass Instrument Company EEG Machine, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Knights, Robert, reports and correspondence, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Korein Report, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Legal/Historical Ganja-Whetton, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Life History Codebook and Code sheets, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Ganja Manuscript Expenses, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Other Studies Correspondence, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Inquiries Re: Ganja Report/Book, 1973-1976 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Congratulatory Letters re: Ganja, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Ganja in Jaimaica (Mouton) (Doubleday), 1970s (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Critique - letters, comments, 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Ganja in Jaimaica - Publicity, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Consumer Reports - Requests & Comments, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - BBC (Jamaica Ganja Study) Tony Edwards, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - NBC - Silverman and Konner, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Ganja in Jamaica Mailing List, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Ganja in Jamaica KTO Press, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Ganja Paperback - Doubleday, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Guyana - Economic Conditions, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Medical Codebook and Code sheets, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - McDonough, Ronald, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Computer Information (misc.), 1970 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, M, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Mailing List - Final Report, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Medical Analysis, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Mouton Publishing - Ganja MS, 1974, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Publishers Regarding Final Report, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Charles Thomas Publisher Correspondence, 1972, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Mosaic Score Sheets, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Census of Medical Hospital Research Institute, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Original Raw Computer Data, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Subject Information, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - National Commission on Marihuana and Drug Abuse, 1970s (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1970s (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - NIMH Materials, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - NIMH/Jamaica Meeting, 1970 June 15 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Other Marihuana Projects, 1960-1980 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Mouton Publishers - Authors' Questionnaires, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Department of Psychiatry (Beaubrun and Staff Correspondence), 1970s (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Report - Beaubrun, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Sample Status, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Sampling Procedure Alligator Pond Notes, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Analysis of Cannabis (NIMH), 1971 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Pantin Drug Report (Trinidad), 1972 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Psychological Codebook and Code sheet, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Psychological Codebook and Code sheet, undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Psychiatric Codebook and code sheet, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Psychological Tests, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Psychological Materials (Stuart, et al.), 1971 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Rastafarian Materials, 1960s (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Reports - Vestegaard, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1971, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Reports to NIMH, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Reports from West Indies, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Research Form, Preliminary, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Rogers, Claudia, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Rogers, Claudia, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Subcontract University of the West Indies (UWI), 1970, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - UWI Correspondence, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Schaeffer, Joseph Sociological Studies, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Schaeffer Report, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Schaeffer Report Original?, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - J. Schaeffer Proposal - Research on Cannabis in Mexico, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Subjects - Life Histories, 1970s (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Supplementary Grant Request (Empty), 1970s (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1970s (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - UWI Meeting Minutes, 1970s (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Telophone Notes NIMH, 1970, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Vera Rubin (V.R.) Ganja (NIMH) Working Notes, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Working Notes Ganja, 1969, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Working Notes V.R., undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Offprints (V.R. Notes), 1970s (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Related Papers Prepared by V.R., 1970s (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - V.R. Working Notes Bibliography, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
- Series III: Reports
  - Effects of Chronic Smoking of Cannabis in Jamaica, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Ganja in Jamaica: A Medical Anthropological Study of Chronic Marihuana Use, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Effects of Chronic Smoking of Cannabis in Jamaica (2 copies), undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Preliminary notes - Law Enforcement and Ganja in Jamaica, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Law Enforcement and Ganja in Jamaica (5 bound copies), undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Journals, Articles, and Reprints
  - Dr. William Schull, 1978-1982 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - P. Masters (Helfman) Racemisation in Dentine, 1978, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Gerontology Research Center (NIA) Richard Greulich, 1970, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Baltimore - VR/SB Tuesday 9/14 - 15, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Research VR Longevity Notes, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Consortium Program (Working Draft), undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Telephone Notes on Aging - VR, 1976, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Drug and Alcohol - Chronic Usage (Articles) 1 of 3, 1970s (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Drug and Alcohol - Chronic Usage (Articles) 2 of 3, 1970s (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Drug and Alcohol - Chronic Usage (Articles) 3 of 3, 1970s (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - The War on Hunger Journal, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Marijuana (Articles) 1 of 2, 1970s (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Marijuana (Articles) 2 of 2, 1970s (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Drug Dependence (Articles) 1 of 2, 1970s (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Drug Dependence (Articles) 2 of 2, 1970s (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Cannabis Reports 1 of 3, 1970s (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Cannabis Reports 2 of 3, 1970s (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Cannabis Reports 3 of 3, 1970s (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Marijuana: The Health Questions, The Legal Questions. (Several Copies), 1975 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Journal Articles about Marijuana Use, 1970s (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Drug Articles Addiction Research Foundation, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Reconciling Unidimensional and Multidimensional Models of Patterns of Drug Use, 1976 May (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Marihuana and the Question of Personal Security, 1975 February (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Hearing before the Sub-Committee to Investigate the Administration of the Internal Security Act and Other Internal Security Laws of the Committee on the Judiciary, U.S. Senate: Part 4 The Global Context; Report of General Walt, 1972 September 14 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Hearing before the Sub-Committee to Investigate the Administration of the Internal Security Act and Other Internal Security Laws of the Committee on the Judiciary, U.S. Senate: Part 5 Research on Marihuana and Hashish, 1972 September 18 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Hearing before the Sub-Committee to Investigate the Administration of the Internal Security Act and Other Internal Security Laws of the Committee on the Judiciary, U.S. Senate: Part 6 The Machinery of Control, 1972 September 18 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Amphetamines, Barbiturates, LSD and Cannabis: Their Use and Misuse, undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Hearing before the Select Committee on Narcotics Abuse and Control House of Representatives, 1979 July 19 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Hearing before the Select Committee on Narcotics Abuse and Control House of Representatives, 1980 May 20 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Health Consequences of Marihuana Abuse: Recent Findings and the Therapeutic Uses of Marihuana and the Use of Heroin to Reduce Pain, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - The West African Students' Union A Study in Culture Contact, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Notes Sur Quelques Vegetaux Utilises Au Cambodge, undated (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Schultes, Hallucinogens of Plant Origins, 1969 January 17 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Lennard et al., Hazards Implicit in Prescribing Psychoactive Drugs, 1970 July 31 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Cannabis and Temporal Disintegration in Experienced and Naïve Subjects, 1973 February 23 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Science (several issues), 1970s (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - The Sciences (several issues), 1976 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Focus on Alcohol and Drug Issues, 1981-1983 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Science Articles, 1970s (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Youth Reporters Discuss "Problem" Drugs, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - An Act to Amend the Dangerous Drugs Law, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - International Control of Drugs with particular reference to the Revised Draft Protocol of Psychotropic Substances, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Annotated Bibliography of Marihuana, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Marijuana A Selective Bibliography, 1924-1970 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Culture and Alcohol Use A Bibliography of Anthropological Studies, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - A Comprehensive Guide to the English-Language Literature on Cannabis, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - List of Medicinal Plants - Jamaica, undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Cannabis Articles, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Conference on the Utilization of Research in Drug Policy Making, Volume 1, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Conference on the Utilization of Research in Drug Policy Making, Volume 2, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - The Harvard Medical School Health Letter, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Sells, A Bibliography on Cannabis Dependence, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Hemp as Medicine, 1970s (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Canada. Commission of Inquiry into the Non-Medical use of Drugs. A Review of Hemp Cultivation in Canada, 1970-1981 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Marihuana and Health, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Marihuana and Health, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - A Guide to Drug Abuse Education and Information Materials, undated (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Marihuana and the Law - National Commission Report, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Rough draft with handwritten corrections of unnamed article about race and drugs, 1970-1981 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Jamaican Bushes and Human Chromosomes, undated (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Special Action Office for Drug Abuse Prevention, 1970s (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Establisment of Commission on Marihuana, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Narcotic Plants - Agricultural Origins (Articles) 1 of 4, 1970s (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Narcotic Plants - Agricultural Origins (Articles) 2 of 4, 1970s (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - Narcotic Plants - Agricultural Origins (Articles) 3 of 4, 1970s (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Narcotic Plants - Agricultural Origins (Articles) 4 of 4, 1970s (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Issues of Contemporary Drug Problems, 1972-1975 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Research Issues Drug Themes in Fiction, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Research Issues Drug Themes in Science Fiction, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - A Cocaine Bibliography-Nonannotated NIDA, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Drugs and Addict Lifestyles NIDA, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Drugs and Death NIDA, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Guide to the Drug Research Literature NIDA, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Perspectives on the History of Psychoactive Substance Use NIDA, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - International Drug Use NIDA, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Research Issues Update, 1978 NIDA, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - National Drug Report - NORML (Various Drug articles), 1970s (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - The Leaflet NORML (Various Drug Articles), 1970s (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Alcoholism and Marijuana Problems (Articles), 1970s (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Bewley, Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Prescribing Clinics for Narcotic Addicts in the United Kingdom (1968-1970) (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Chopra and Chopra, The Use of the Cannabis Drugs in India, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Summary and Conclusions (Ganja Study), undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - 20/20, 1978 November 30 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - New Potential Hazard Regarding Use of Marijuana - Treatment of Plants with Liquid Fertilizers, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Mescaline and Peyote, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Rituals of Euphoria: Coca in South America, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - A Woman's Choice Deciding About Drugs, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Drugs of Abuse, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Educational Materials Catalogue, undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Drug Abuse Council Annual Report, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Analysis of LSD Flashback, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Nightwatch SGS Newsmagazine (3 copies), 1975 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - El Contexto Cultural De Un Alucinogeno Aborigen: Banisteriopsis Caapi, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Anderson, The Pot Lobby, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Medical Tribune and Medical News Vol 14, No 39, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Consumer Reports, 1975 March, 1975 April (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Psychology Today, 1971 May (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - National Review, 1975 June 6 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Science News, 1976 October 30 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Drug Abuse Services Winter Reports, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Scientific American Reprint: Marihuana, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - New Society No. 402, 1970 June 11 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Yearbook of Physical Anthropology, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Yearbook of Physical Anthropology, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Caribbean Medical Journal Vol. XXX, No. 1-4, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Journal of Psychedelic Drugs, 1970, 1971, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Journal of Ethno-Pharmacology Vol. 1, No. 4, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - High Times, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Science News, 1976 January 31 (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - NORML 10th Anniversary, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - British Medical Journal, 1971 May 8 (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Head Monthly April and March, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - Natual History, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - Scientific American, 1979 December (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - Caribbean Review Val VII, No. 1, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - World Anthropology Group 1, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - Center for Socio-Cultural Research, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - Bulletin on Narcotics UN, 1965 March (Box 37, Folder 39)
  - Articles on the Epidemiology of Drugs, 1920, 1998 (Box 37, Folder 40)
  - Articles on Heroin, 1920, 1998 (Box 37, Folder 41)
  - Articles on Race and Drug Use, 1991, 1997, 1998 (Box 37, Folder 42)
  - Articles on Botany and Cannabis, 1960, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 1, Barcode data_value_missing_22d5338b5355cab41e6e73e2385313d7)
  - Articles on Drug Use in America, 1970, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 2, Barcode data_value_missing_a42b07077883637f21ef0e4b1e206dab)
  - Drug Abuse Prevention: The Awareness, Experience and Opinions of Junior and Senior High School Students in New York State, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 3, Barcode data_value_missing_df3efa71fb11b661e1b853121267eeda)
  - Annotated Bibliography of Research Reports and Program Studies, 1975 (Box 43, Folder 4, Barcode data_value_missing_2efb4e4316109e40f241075238e2d6ed)
  - Playboy, 1975 March (Box 43, Folder 5, Barcode data_value_missing_b750892b0066ef2fefd6c99ba65e6693)
  - Columbia Forum vol. XII no. 4, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 6, Barcode data_value_missing_09a24f7bd17a34640592d5158d4bbd5d)
- Series V: Newspapers and Clippings
  - News clippings, 1974-1977 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Ganja Newspaper Clips, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Marihuana News Clipping, 1969-1974 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Marihuana News Clipping, 1972-1977 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Marihuana News Clipping, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Marihuana News Clipping, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Ganja News Clippings from Jamaica, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Marihuana News Clipping, 1977-1978 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Ganja Newspaper Articles, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Marihuana News Clipping, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Marijuana News Clipping, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Marihuana News Clipping, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings (W. I.), 1970s (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - The Journal Newspaper (almost full runs), 1980-1981 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Life, 1969 October 31 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Ganja - The Daily Gleaner, 1972 June 13 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Marijuana Study by US Finds no Serious Harms - New York Times, 1975 July 9 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Life In Jamaica's Ganja Culture - Tropic, The Miami Herald, 1976 May 16 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - The Gleaner Jamaican Weekly, 1977 March 29 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - The New York Times Briefing Papers for Public Affairs, 1970s (Box 41, Folder 5)